<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.2" packageId="cos-spu.108.1" xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0/eml.xsd" system="edi">
  <access authSystem="https://pasta.edirepository.org/authentication" order="allowFirst" scope="document">
    <allow>
      <principal>uid=EDI,o=EDI,dc=edirepository,dc=org</principal>
      <permission>all</permission>
    </allow>
    <allow>
      <principal>public</principal>
      <permission>read</permission>
    </allow>
  </access>
  <dataset>
    <title>Long Term Aquatic Monitoring (LTAM) Pebble Count, 2006-2017</title>
    <creator>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Amy</givenName>
        <surName>Reichenbach</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>EDI/SPU to confirm</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>EDI/SPU to confirm</electronicMailAddress>
    </creator>
    <associatedParty>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Amy</givenName>
        <surName>Reichenbach</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>EDI/SPU to confirm</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>EDI/SPU to confirm</electronicMailAddress>
      <role>publisher</role>
    </associatedParty>
    <pubDate>2024-05-08</pubDate>
    <abstract>
      <para>Long Term Aquatic Monitoring (LTAM) pebble count data and summary analysis, 2006-2017, in support of the Cedar River Watershed Habitat Conservation Plan, for Seattle Public Utilities in North Bend, Washington. Field methods were based on Woman Pebble Count methods, bankfull to bankfull, for all channels at a particular cross section, blind touch method, and for at least 100 particles.</para>
    </abstract>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword>Pebble count</keyword>
      <keyword>Long Term Aquatic Monitoring</keyword>
      <keyword>LTAM</keyword>
    </keywordSet>
    <intellectualRights>
      <para>This data package is released to the "public domain" under Creative Commons CC0 1.0 "No Rights Reserved" (see: https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). It is considered professional etiquette to provide attribution of the original work if this data package is shared in whole or by individual components. A generic citation is provided for this data package on the website https://portal.edirepository.org (herein "website") in the summary metadata page. Communication (and collaboration) with the creators of this data package is recommended to prevent duplicate research or publication. This data package (and its components) is made available "as is" and with no warranty of accuracy or fitness for use. The creators of this data package and the website shall not be liable for any damages resulting from misinterpretation or misuse of the data package or its components. Periodic updates of this data package may be available from the website. Thank you.
</para>
    </intellectualRights>
    <coverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription>Study site</geographicDescription>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-121.77</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-121.77</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>47.6199</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>47.6199</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <temporalCoverage>
        <rangeOfDates>
          <beginDate>
            <calendarDate>2006-01-01</calendarDate>
          </beginDate>
          <endDate>
            <calendarDate>2017-01-01</calendarDate>
          </endDate>
        </rangeOfDates>
      </temporalCoverage>
    </coverage>
    <maintenance>
      <description>Update if data is collected after 2017.</description>
    </maintenance>
    <contact>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Amy</givenName>
        <surName>Reichenbach</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>EDI/SPU to confirm</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>EDI/SPU to confirm</electronicMailAddress>
    </contact>
    <publisher>
      <individualName>
        <givenName>Amy</givenName>
        <surName>Reichenbach</surName>
      </individualName>
      <organizationName>EDI/SPU to confirm</organizationName>
      <electronicMailAddress>EDI/SPU to confirm</electronicMailAddress>
    </publisher>
    <methods>
      <methodStep>
        <description>
          <para>The methods for pebble count data collection were based on the Wolman Pebble count method. The b-axis (medium axis) of the sediment particle to the nearest mm using a see-through ruler.  Make sure the markings on the ruler have not rubbed off and are very clear (if a ruler is kept in the backpack all field season some of the markings will have rubbed off by the end of the field season).  For measurements &lt; 2 mm record "1".  Do not assume a particle is &lt; 2 mm without measuring it first.  Each axis (a, b, and c) are perpendicular to each other.  It is usually easiest to find the c-axis (long axis) then work in a perpendicular fashion to find the a-axis (short axis) and finally the b-axis.  Sometimes two axes are very similar which will require measuring both axes to determine which one is the b-axis.  Choose each particle in a systematic and random fashion for the entire transect (usually a blind touch with the forefinger off the tip of your boot).  The pace must be consistent for the entire transect although pace can be different between transects.  A transect must be finished regardless if the desired goal is met mid-transect. </para>
        </description>
      </methodStep>
    </methods>
    <otherEntity>
      <entityName>SIMS_LTAMPebbleCount_GraphsTables</entityName>
      <entityDescription>Excel workbook that has the analysis for pebble count data (graphs, tables, formulas, and statistics). The workbook contains conditional formatting. This file will be useful if the data steward wants to replicate the analysis in the future.</entityDescription>
      <physical>
        <objectName>SIMS_LTAMPebbleCount_GraphsTables.xlsx</objectName>
        <size unit="bytes">4113288</size>
        <authentication method="MD5">7ca73ce1e5e1c186c6ef11842a14ec94</authentication>
        <dataFormat>
          <externallyDefinedFormat>
            <formatName>application/vnd.openxmlformats-officedocument.spreadsheetml.sheet</formatName>
          </externallyDefinedFormat>
        </dataFormat>
      </physical>
      <entityType>unknown</entityType>
    </otherEntity>
  </dataset>
  <additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <emlEditor>
        <app>EMLassemblyline</app>
        <release>3.5.5</release>
      </emlEditor>
    </metadata>
  </additionalMetadata>
</eml:eml>
